The Mesh Renderer.
Mesh Renderer について、みていきます。
To render a mesh we need 2 components.
メッシュをレンダリングするにはふたつのコンポーネントが必要です。
The Mesh Filter
メッシュフィルタ（Mesh Filter） および
and the Mesh Renderer.
メッシュレンダラ（Mesh Renderer） です。
When importing a mesh model
メッシュ モデルをインポートするとき
Unity will automatically create a
Unity は自動的に
prefab asset that includes a mesh filter
プレハブ アセットを作成します。
component to hold the mesh data for the model
これにはメッシュ フィルタ コンポーネントが含まれ、モデルのためのメッシュデータを格納し、
and a mesh renderer component
さらにメッシュレンダラ コンポーネントが含まれ、
to render this mesh data in our scene.
シーンのメッシュデータをレンダリングします。
The mesh renderer does not
メッシュレンダラは
render skinned meshes.
スキン メッシュのレンダリングをしません。
Skinned meshes are used for rendering characters.
スキン メッシュはキャラクターのレンダリングに使用されます。
Characters are animated using bones
キャラクターはボーンを使用してアニメーションします。
and every bone effects part of the mesh.
そしてすべてのボーンはメッシュの一部を影響します。
If the model is skinned,
もしモデルがスキニングされている場合、
Unity will create a skinned mesh renderer
Unity はインポートされたモデルのために
for the imported model instead.
スキン メッシュ レンダラを作成します。
Information on skinned mesh renderers
スキン メッシュ レンダラに関する情報は
can be found in another lesson.
別のレッスンで見つけることが出来ます。
Each mesh asset needs it's own mesh filter
各々のメッシュ アセットは自身のメッシュ フィルタおよび
and mesh renderer.
メッシュ レンダラが必要です。
If the model is made of several
もしモデルがいくつかの異なったメッシュから
separate meshes each will have it's own
構成されている場合、それぞれが
prefab game object with it's own
プレハブ ゲームオブジェクトと
mesh filter - mesh renderer pair.
メッシュ フィルタ とメッシュ レンダラ のペアを保有します。
The mesh filter holds the mesh data of the model
メッシュフィルタはモデルのメッシュ データを保有して、
and passes it to the mesh renderer
メッシュレンダラに渡して、
for rendering on screen.
画面にレンダリングします。
The mesh filter component
メッシュ フィルタ コンポーネントは
has only one property and this is
プロパティがひとつしかなく、
a reference to the mesh asset itself.
これはメッシュ アセット自身への参照です。
The mesh renderer takes the mesh model
メッシュ レンダラはメッシュ モデルデータを
data from the mesh filter and renders
メッシュ フィルタから取得して
it in our scene at the position,
シーン上のオブジェクトの
rotation and scale defined by
Transform コンポーネントの
the object's transform component.
位置、回転、スケールどおりにレンダリングします。
The mesh renderer has properties that
メッシュ レンダラには
define how the model will be rendered
モデルがどのようにレンダリングされるか、
or drawn in our scene.
またはシーン上で描画されるか定義するプロパティがあります。
These fall in to 3 broad categories.
これらは 大きく分けて 3 つのカテゴリーに分かれます。
Shadows, materials and light probes.
シャドウ、マテリアル、およびライトプローブです。
With shadows, if there is a shadow
シャドウには、オブジェクトにシャドウつきの
casting light on the object we can
ライトがある場合、
set whether the mesh renderer will
メッシュ レンダラが
cast and or receive shadows.
シャドウを投影するか、シャドウを投影されるか、オプションとしてセットできます。
Next there is a list of materials
次にオブジェクトをレンダリングする
to render the object with.
マテリアルのリストがあります。
Unity needs at least one material assigned
Unity は少なくともひとつのマテリアルを
to the mesh renderer to be able to draw
メッシュレンダラにアサインしないと
that object in our scene.
シーン上にそのオブジェクトを描画できません。
For more information on materials themselves
マテリアル自身に関するより多くの情報については
see the appropriate lesson.
それに応じたレッスンを参照して下さい。
Meshes imported in to Unity can
Unity にインポートされたメッシュは
use multiple materials, if the mesh
モデルがもとのモデリングアプリケーションで
model has been setup to do so
セットアップされていれば
in the original modelling application.
複数のマテリアルを使用することが出来ます。
The mesh renderer maintains a list
メッシュ レンダラは
simply called Materials for all materials
メッシュ モデルにより使用される
used by the mesh model.
Materials と呼ばれるマテリアルの一覧を保持します。
Often this list only contains one material.
多くの場合このリストにはひとつのマテリアルのみ含まれます。
This materials list should have one slot
このマテリアル リストは、
in the list for each sub mesh
in the list for each sub mesh
on the mesh model.
ひとつのスロットがあるべきです。
If any given slot has no material assigned
もしスロットにマテリアルが何もアサインされてなければ
the associated mesh will show pink
対応するメッシュはピンク色となり、
indicating that the material is missing.
そのマテリアルがないことを示します。
Lastly, there are light probes.
最後に、ライトプローブです。
A mesh can be lit by light probes.
メッシュはライト プローブによりライティングできます。
Light probes sample the lighting of a scene
ライト プローブはシーンのライティングを
at a point and cast that light on
ある地点でサンプリングして
on to the rendered mesh.
レンダリングされたメッシュにライトを当てます。
This is often used in conjunction
これはしばしば
with light mapping.
ライトマッピングとともに使われます。
Light probes light dynamic objects
ライトプローブ は
such as characters that would not receive
ライトマップからの焼き込みされたライティング情報を受けないキャラクターなど
baked lighting information from a light map.
動的オブジェクトをライティングします。
To use light probes,
ライトプローブを使用するためには
the Use Light Probes option must be enabled.
Use Light Probes オプションを有効化する必要があります。
For more information on light probes,
ライトプローブの詳細、
including the Anchor Override property,
Anchor Override プロパティを含めて、
please see the appropriate lesson
対応するレッスンを参照して、
and documentation link below.
下にあるドキュメントのリンクを確認して下さい。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)